<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[john hammond]]></title>
  <link href="http://jvh1979.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jvh1979.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-05T16:12:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jvh1979.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[john hammond]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death and Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://jvh1979.github.io/blog/2014/11/05/death-and-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T15:00:10-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jvh1979.github.io/blog/2014/11/05/death-and-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok, I realize this is a very odd title.  &ldquo;Death&rdquo; and &ldquo;Want&rdquo; have been two words I&rsquo;ve been pondering these past few days.  A little backstory.
As some of you know, I love comics and the culture that embraces them.  I&rsquo;ve been a fan since I was very young, and I have been very lucky to make some great friends through my hobby.  One of which is a guy named Jeremy Dale.  Jeremy was a indie comic artist/creator, and his most recent work was a kid&rsquo;s adventure book name &ldquo;Skyward&rdquo;.  Jeremy was incredibly skilled as an illustrator, and his style was very animated and a throwback to the simpler times of childhood.  He was always such a nice and friendly guy. He never spoke negatively about anything or anyone, always super supportive. Jeremy and his wife, Kelly, made any event they were present for more memorable and fun.
One evening earlier this week, Jeremy passed away suddenly.  From what we were told he passed surrounded by friends and family, and he passed without much pain or struggle.  This has been quite a shock.  This news always is.  Jeremy and I are close in age, so it&rsquo;s yet another reminder about mortality.
Death is one of the few absolutes in life.  My outlook on this subject has shifted many times over the years.  For as many friends I&rsquo;m lucky to have in life, I have lost quite a few people in this early stage. But do we really lose someone?
I feel life is just a ton of learning and experiences that shape up the story of you.  With that being said memories persevere, thus things you have learned or experiences you have had are still there.  Sure, they may have a ton of other thoughts and memories that bury them, but they are there. I believe in dealing with death, you are presented a choice.  You choose the path that you go in light of that happening.  You can choose to walk through the stages of grief or you can celebrate the person who died.  I choose to celebrate.
I know that anytime I attend a comic book convention now, it will be different.  I won&rsquo;t get to see Jeremy sitting dilligently behind a table sketching, looking up to flash an acknowledging grin. With him not being there, we lost a really positive, friendly guy.  That means to celebrate Jeremy, we have to be a little nicer to people. Be a little more supportive to someone. To be a little more excited about this artform we all love, because Jeremy isn&rsquo;t there to help foster that excitement.  It won&rsquo;t be easy, and it shouldn&rsquo;t be, but that&rsquo;s what we do.
I hate this loss for his amazing wife, Kelly. She fortunately has quite a few friends, supporters, and fans that will be there to try to help her and his family get through this. But hopefully, she will see the effect that Jeremy has had on so many people and that will comfort her.
So how does &ldquo;want&rdquo; come into play here?
It&rsquo;s a word that keeps coming to my attention lately. What do I want in life? Where do I want to work? What do I want to learn next? Where do I want to be in five years? What do I want for dinner? Who do I want to join me on this ride called life?
Wanting things is a natural aspect of being a human. We are taught it very early in life even. I&rsquo;ve been wrestling with my wants allot lately, and the impact of those decisions on myself and others. Then it hit me last night upon hearing the news about Jeremy.
These are my wants in a very short list.
<li>I want to be the best developer I can be.
<li>I want to be the best father I can be.
<li>I want to be the best co-worker I can be.
<li>I want to be the best friend I can be.
<li>I want to be the best human I can be.<br>
<br>By just wanting whats best for me and those associated with me, I think it takes some of the pressure and anxiety out of it. With this news about Jeremy, it has made me focus and evaluate whats next for me. I&rsquo;m thankful for that. I&rsquo;m grateful for meeting Jeremy Dale and this is how I choose to remember him, by being better. That&rsquo;s how I choose to honor this awesome artist I know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></title>
    <link href="http://jvh1979.github.io/blog/2014/10/28/the-iron-yard/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-28T09:12:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jvh1979.github.io/blog/2014/10/28/the-iron-yard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://theironyard.com/images/iron-yard-logo.svg"></p>

<p>As of late, I have been getting quite a few questions about my experience at The Iron Yard.  For those unfamiliar, The Iron Yard is an intense, twelve week coding &ldquo;boot camp&rdquo;.  The school currently has twelve locations accross the country.  I have just graduated with a certificate in ruby on rails engineering. It&rsquo;s been such an awesome experience for me, and I would love to share it with you.
Usually the first question I get is &ldquo;why?&rdquo;.
Well I really wasn&rsquo;t happy with where my life was going.  I have been working in the food and beverage industry for the last ten years, and I&rsquo;ve loved it but desperately needed change.  My work was becoming more and more monotonous.  I didn&rsquo;t really feel appreciated by the people I was working for and with.  To be honest, I was beginning to feel helpless.  Since I was young, I have been a creative individual. It started with doodling my favorite cartoon characthers and building odd structures out of legos.  By this point in my life, I felt this aspect of me was being stifled.<br/>
I wanted to work with design and internet technologies when I graduated high school, but a simple cost/benefit analysis,  an oversaturated job market, and a girl lead me on an alternate path.  A little girl named Kailey entered my life, and I became a father.  Priorities changed drastically, and her well being became my only concern.  I began a career in customer service and management, both in retail and food and beverage.  That changed when I saw a billboard,&ldquo;Learn to Code, Get a job&rdquo;.  The tech community in Charleston has been rapidly growing these last few years, and the time was clearly right.  I submitted an application, and then the interview process began.  I met with my future mentors, Sally, Calvin, and Nick; and so it began.  On the morning of July 21st, my life changed for the better.
On that morning, I found myself in a room with fifteen awesome, brilliant, anxious individuals as we started down this new path.  We were thrown right in, and it was grueling. Limits were tested mentally, physically, and emotionally.  But fortunately we had an awesome instructor in Nick Bucciarelli.  He patiently pushed this down this path and helped us reach the potential he saw in us when we interviewed.
As of today, months after that morning in July, I am full stack developer and Ruby on Rails Engineer.  As much as I feel accomplished, I know I am still very green.  I have a renewed love for learning and with that really figuring out who I am.  I have made new friends and future co workers.  I wake up every morning wondering what I&rsquo;m going to build instead of just submitting to the same routine.  This experience has been so empowering.  If this is something you&rsquo;re considering, I strongly suggest you do it.  You would be shocked the difference three months can make.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://jvh1979.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/first/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T09:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://jvh1979.github.io/blog/2014/10/27/first</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m John, and I&rsquo;m a ruby on rails engineer.
I grew up in North Myrtle Beach, SC.
I currently reside in Charleston, SC.
I am passionate about technology, food, and expression.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
